(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
- ERROR
Covered by 常闇トワ
Covered by Tokoyami Towa
作詞・作曲：niki
Lyrics/Composition: niki
見えるこの目の　涙
The tears in these eyes I can see,
命の色に　滲んでいる
Are blurring with the color of life
何を残して　与えた？
What did I leave behind and give?
問いかけて　潰れて
I ask and am crushed
青と赤色　混ざる
In this world where blue and red mix,
この世の中で　叫んでいる
I am screaming
何を求めて　歩いた？
What did I walk in search of?
追いかけて　疲れて
I chased it and got tired
どのくらい　異常？
To what extent is it an abnormality?
壊れているの？
Is it broken?
壊れているよ
It is broken
それでも　息を　したい
Even so, I want to breathe,
したい
I want to
君に見える
Visible to you
エルナ...
Error...
...夢の様に最後の...
...like a dream, for the last...
...言葉も詰まるよ エルナ
...words get stuck, error.
遠い日のこと...
About a distant day...
...淡い光が空に溢れている
...a faint light overflows the sky.
何を選んで並べた...
What did I choose and line up...
...涙色重ねて
...layering the colors of tears.
浮かぶその体 意識の中...
That floating body, within consciousness...
...溶けて滲んでしまう
...it melts and blurs.
何を見てきて比べた...
What did I see and compare...
...悲しくて煩って
...suffering in sadness.
どのくらい以上...
How much more...
...歪んでいるの？
...is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It's distorted.
それでも...
Even so...
...息をしたい したい
...I want to breathe, I want to.
夢を見ているの...
Are you dreaming...
...思う君に最後の...
...of you, I thought, for the last...
...言葉も詰まるよ エルナ
...words get stuck, error.
数えることも 失うことも...
Neither counting nor losing...
...忘れることもできないの
...can I forget.
暴れ出すこのエラーを殺して...
Killing this error that's breaking out...
...嗤う僕が待った
...the laughing me waited.
壊しているの？
Are you breaking it?
壊して知るの
I'll know by breaking it.
それでも...
Even so...
...涙したい したい
...I want to cry, I want to.
君に届いたの？
Did it reach you?
歌う声に最後の...
In the singing voice, the last...
...言葉並べても
...even if I line up the words.
重なる色に滲んで
Blurring into the overlapping colors.
壊れているの？
Is it broken?
壊れているよ
It's broken.
それでも...
Even so...
...息をしたい したい
...I want to breathe, I want to.
君に見えてたの？
Could you see it?
夢の様に最後の...
Like a dream, for the last...
...言葉も詰まるよ エルナ
...words get stuck, error.
はーい！みんなー！こんやっぴー！常闇トワでーす！
Hi everyone! Kon-yappi! It's Tokoyami Towa!
明けましておめでとうございまーす！
Happy New Year!
1月3日、えー、常闇トワ、なんと3周年を迎えることができました！
On January 3rd, I, Tokoyami Towa, have reached my 3rd anniversary!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ふぅ...どうでしたか？
Whew... How was that?
はい、今歌った曲はですね、nikiさんの「ERROR」という曲でしたー！
Yes, the song I just sang was "ERROR" by niki!
カバー曲の中でトワが投稿した中で一番再生されてて、ま、みんなもね、結構知ってくれてる曲なんじゃないかなと思っております。
Among the cover songs I've posted, it's the most played one, so I think many of you are familiar with it.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ふぅ...ありがとう！
Whew... Thank you!
なんかもう、すごい拍手と、紫のハートとかもね、ありがとね！見えてるよー！
The applause and purple hearts are amazing, thank you! I can see them!
はい、ということで今日はね、ハッシュタグなんですけれども、#常闇トワ3周年記念LIVE で呟いてください。
Yes, and for today's hashtag, please tweet using #TokoyamiTowa3rdAnniversaryLive.
よろしく！目指せトレンド1位！おっほっほーい！
Please! Let's aim for #1 on trending! Oh-ho-hoy!
はい、ということでね、本日もトワということで連発していきたいと思います！
Yes, and so, I'm going to keep going with more Towa today!
はい、今日の配信タイトルなんですけれども、「MIX2」というタイトルになっておりまして、
Yes, today's stream is titled "MIX2".
前回、生誕祭で「MIX」というタイトルの配信をやらせていただいたんですけれども、
Last time, for my birthday, I did a stream titled "MIX".
その時ね、ま、あのそのホロライブメンバーの曲をそのホロライブメンバーと一緒に歌って踊るということをしたんですね。
At that time, I sang and danced to Hololive members' songs together with those Hololive members.
で、その時にね、いっぱいね、悩んだんですよ、いっぱい歌いたい曲があって。
I had a hard time deciding then, because there were so many songs I wanted to sing.
で、あー、でも、時間が...っていうことで、ま、何名かに声をかけさせていただいたんですけれども、
But because of time constraints, I only reached out to a few people.
まだまだ歌い切りたい曲と、一緒にね、踊りたい人とかいっぱいいたので、
Since there are still many songs I want to sing and people I want to dance with,
今回はまた前回とは違うメンバーをお呼びして、やっていきたいと思います！イエーイ！
this time, I've invited different members from last time! Yay!
はい、ではこの後はね、ゲストパートになります。
Alright, next up is the guest part.
本当にね、あの歌もね、ダンスもね、すごい頑張ったので、楽しんで見ていただけたらなと思います。
I worked really hard on both the singing and dancing, so I hope you enjoy watching it.
では最後まで楽しんでください！どうぞ！
Please enjoy until the end! Here we go!
暗い方ばっか見てないで
Don't just look at the dark side
ウラパパパラリラ 踊れよ
Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra, dance away!
魔界学校の優等生
The honor student of the Demon World Academy
華やかなワガママ 漂え
Let your elegant selfishness drift
イナイイナイばぁでこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look this way
したたかな未来を咲かせよ
Make a resilient future bloom
期待相まって高まって
Expectations grow and heighten
溜まったMP放て黒魔術
Release your stored MP, black magic!
我に続け今宵の
Follow me tonight
闇に震えかけろよ
Shiver and run through the darkness
切に響く言葉は
The words that resonate deeply are
ぶち切れハッキョーパラダイス
A snap-crazy paradise!
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも私の元で
Stay by my side from now on
不思議な力打ち放って
Release your mysterious power
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile
ウラパパパラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra
一生一緒だよ、ね
We'll be together forever, okay?
暗いもん隠してないで
Don't hide the dark things
鈍った体さらば踊れよ
Say goodbye to your dull body and dance!
視界外目逸らさないで
Don't look away beyond your sight
今はただ離れてかないで
Right now, just don't leave me
いやんいやん待ってあっち向いて
No, no, wait, look over there
今はまだ心の準備を
I'm still getting my heart ready
期待相まって高まって
Expectations grow and heighten
ウラパパパ動け黒魔術
Ura-pa-pa-pa, move, black magic!
我に続け今宵の
Follow me tonight
闇を破れメシアよ
Break through the darkness, Messiah
討つべきものその名は
The thing that must be struck down, its name is
眠りの発狂パラダイス
Sleepy-snap-crazy paradise!
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll make it clear for you
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandish your mysterious power
皆で笑顔になっちゃって
Making everyone smile
ウラパパパラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
ヒラリヒラリと紫に染まって
Fluttering and fluttering, dyed in violet
これからもあなたの元で
Stay by your side from now on
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Release the miracle spell
咲かせる笑顔の花を
Making flowers of smiles bloom
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも変わらないままで
Staying just as we are from now on
不思議な力ほら宿って
Look, a mysterious power dwells within
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile
ウラパパパラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa-pa-ra-ri-ra
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対一緒だよね
Definitely together forever, right?
Ready step, take a step, yeah
恋は薔薇色ナイト
Love is a rose-colored night
夢をのせて踊りましょう
Let's dance with our dreams
もっと触れたい 知りたい 隠した想い
I want to touch you more, know more, the hidden feelings
月が綺麗なロマンティック
The moon is beautiful, so romantic
時には甘く 熟れた果実のように
Sometimes sweet, like a ripened fruit
君にそっと囁くわ
I'll whisper softly to you
情熱のさざなみに ねぇ
In the ripples of passion, hey
本当の素顔見せて
Show me your true self
ギミギミラ ギミギミラ
Gimme gimme love, gimme gimme love
私のすべてを
All of me
クレイジークレイジーラブ クレイジークレイジーラブ
Crazy crazy love, crazy crazy love
本気見せてあげる
I'll show you I'm serious
アブラカダブラ アブラカダブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
君と出会えた奇跡に
To the miracle of meeting you
アブラカダブラ アブラカダブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
愛をこめて踊りましょう
Let's dance with all our love
こうして笑って 悩んで 迷える日々も なんて素敵なドラマティック
Smiling, worrying, and getting lost in these days—how wonderfully dramatic.
そうやって探って 感じて 重ね合わせて 君にちょっと近づくの
In that way, searching, feeling, and layering it all together, I get a little closer to you.
心臓が叫ぶくらい ほら
Look, to the point where my heart screams.
煩悩を強く光らせて
Make my worldly desires shine brightly.
そうよ Gimme gimme love Gimme gimme love 溶かしてあげるわ
That's right, gimme gimme love, gimme gimme love, I'll melt you down.
きっと Fallin' Fallin' love Fallin' Fallin' love 満ちて 止められないの
Surely fallin' fallin' love, fallin' fallin' love, overflowing and unstoppable.
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ こんな素晴らしい世界に
Abracadabra, abracadabra, in this wonderful world...
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 君のために踊りましょう
...abracadabra, abracadabra, let's dance for you.
まるで ギリギリで ギリギリの 私の心を
Like my heart that's on the edge, on the very edge...
ベイビー 君だけに 君だけに 全部届けたいよ
...baby, I want to deliver it all to you and only you.
待って Gimme gimme love Gimme gimme love 私のすべてを
Wait, gimme gimme love, gimme gimme love, all of me...
だって Crazy Crazy love Crazy Crazy love 本気見せてあげる
...because crazy crazy love, crazy crazy love, I'll show you I'm serious.
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 君と出会えた奇跡に
Abracadabra, abracadabra, to the miracle of meeting you...
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ 愛を込めて踊りましょう
...abracadabra, abracadabra, let's dance with love.
NEXT GUEST
ROBOCOSAN
ねえドクター ねえドクター メンテしてよドクター またいつもの例のバグ
Hey doctor, hey doctor, maintenance me doctor, it's that usual bug again.
ハッピー アラモード 生き生きするモード 踏み立て ゼンマイ式の心
Happy à la mode, lively mode, a freshly wound clockwork heart.
お口ね お口ね くだらないね Yeah Yeah 訳ないね 訳ないね ハイスペックなんで
Mouth, mouth, it's pointless, yeah yeah. No problem, no problem, since I'm high-spec.
実際 最先端のパッ やらなきゃ損さ ドキドキが止まりそう ねじ巻いて
Actually, state-of-the-art "pa!", it's a waste not to do it. My heart feels like it's going to stop, so wind the spring.
リルビ なんて愉快 ヘッドリービ ねじ巻いてよ ねじ巻いてよ ちょっとだけね ちょっちょっとちょっとだけね
Lilvi, how pleasant. Head-lib, wind it up, wind it up, just a little bit, just a-just a-just a little bit.
ぴっぽぱっぽ鳴らして 夢を作って ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Beep-bo-pap-bo, ringing out and making dreams, just a little bit, just a little bit.
でも ちょっちょっとだけじゃ そのうち 足んなくなるかも リルビ リルビ リルビ もっと
But if it's just a-just a little bit, before long it might not be enough. Lilvi, lilvi, lilvi, more.
ねえドクター メンテしてあのドクター
Hey doctor, please maintain that doctor.
てからん てからん てからん てからん 次元の呪いなんて 払おう
Tekaran, tekaran, tekaran, tekaran. Let's cast away this dimensional curse.
満更でもないね 臆さないね とんでもないね Yeah Yeah これはもうテクのだ テクノロジーだ
It's not bad, not afraid, unbelievable, yeah yeah. This is already techno, technology.
新感覚だ 手に持ってるもの 分かったらその手ですぐ巻いて
A new sensation. If you understand what's in your hands, wind it up right away.
リルビ 頑固も笑って ねじ巻いてよ ねじ巻いてよ ちょっとだけね ちょっちょっとちょっとだけね
Lilvi, even the stubbornness laughs. Wind the spring, wind the spring, just a little bit, just a-just a-just a little bit.
君が見さくも笑わせてあげる ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
I'll make you laugh even if you're reluctant, just a little bit, just a little bit.
ほら てからんてからんてからん アイデンティティ アップデートして 止まりかけの心から リルビ リルビ
Look, tekaran tekaran tekaran. Update your identity from this heart about to stop. Lilvi, lilvi.
ぴっぽぱっぽ ぴっぽぱっぽ ぴー カラクリ幸せ おきて おきて 電機ひつじ
Beep-bo-pap-bo, beep-bo-pap-bo, beep. Clockwork happiness. Wake up, wake up, electric sheep.
こっちらにお越しあそばせ
Come over here, if you please
その腕にひとまずネジ巻いて
First, wind the spring on that arm
なんてったってエヴリデイ ネジ巻いてネジ巻いてよ
Because every day, wind it, wind it up
ちょっとだけね ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっとだけね
Just a little, just a, just a, just a little
拝め！ 夢を作る
Worship! Creating a dream
ちょっとだけね ほんのちょっとだけね
Just a little, just a tiny bit
盲目でもなんでもいいけど明日にちょっとだけ巻いて
Being blind or anything is fine, but wind it a bit for tomorrow
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little, just a little
こんな毎日も悪くないよ
A daily life like this isn't bad either
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little, just a little
でもちょっとだけじゃ そのうち 足りなくなるかも
But just a little might not be enough soon
リルビ リルビ リルビ...
Lil' Bi, Lil' Bi, Lil' Bi...
NoDistance
退屈を並べては皆ふららイエイ
Everyone's drifting by, lining up their boredom, yeah
理屈だなんてゴミ箱へ
Throw logic into the trash can
身に覚えあるんでしょ Answer
You recognize this, don't you? Answer
チクチク痛いのね
It's a prickly pain, isn't it?
リゴリズム踊らされて
Dancing to rigorism
蝕まれてく アレ？ アレ？
Being eroded, huh? Huh?
火に焼付けて 悪までも
Sear it in fire, even if it's evil
癒してあげましょう
I'll heal you
ああ お目覚めですか
Ah, are you awake?
ディンドンディンドン 響かせディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, let it ring, ding dong
笑えハッハと叫べ
Laugh "ha ha" and shout
ディンドンディンドン 鳴らせよディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, ring it out, ding dong
病むのが先か 止むのがお先か
Is falling ill first, or is it stopping ahead?
噛みつきはしないわ
I won't bite
慰めもしないわ
I won't comfort you either
私のものね
You're mine
飽きたらNoDistance
When you're tired of it, NoDistance
闇間に溶け甘いチョコ溶かしてく
Melting in the darkness, melting sweet chocolate
食べて崩し投げ捨ては説いてく
Eating, breaking, throwing away and preaching
借り尽くし暴き出し瞳汚してく
Borrowing all, exposing and soiling the eyes
傷が痛むのね
The wound hurts, doesn't it?
メカニズム踊らされて
Dancing to the mechanism
蝕まれてく アレ？ アレ？
Being eroded, huh? Huh?
間違えても正しくても
Whether it's wrong or right
愛してあげましょう
I'll love you
ああ まだダメですか
Ah, is it still no good?
ディンドンディンドン 狂わせディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, drive them mad, ding dong
最後にはッハと叫べ
Shout "ha ha" at the end
ディンドンディンドン 迷わずディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, without hesitation, ding dong
冷める前に 口づけを
Give me a kiss before it cools down
ディンドンディンドン 響かせディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, let it ring, ding dong
笑えハッハと叫べ
Laugh "ha ha" and shout
ディンドンディンドン 鳴らせよディンドン
Ding dong, ding dong, ring it out, ding dong
病むのが先か 止むのがお先か
Is falling ill first, or is it stopping ahead?
噛みつきはしないわ
I won't bite
慰めもしないわ
I won't comfort you either
私のものね
You're mine
飽きたらNoDistance
When you're tired of it, NoDistance
エヴァーブルー
太陽が地平線に飲み込まれるのを
Ever Blue
Watching the sun being swallowed by the horizon
眺めていた
I was watching it
まぶたを閉じれば 私も消えてしまえるような
As if I could disappear too if I closed my eyes
気がしたのに
I felt that way
午前8時10時12分 生活の雑音を
8 AM, 10 AM, 12 PM, the noise of daily life
バカになったふりして
Pretending to have become stupid
不自然もない 心の鏡は曇っている
Nothing is unnatural; the mirror of my heart is clouded.
脱ぎ捨てた服さえ余所余所しい
Even the clothes I threw off feel like a stranger.
ここは底なしの海
This is a bottomless sea.
悲しくはない
I'm not sad.
苦しくもない
I'm not in pain.
さみしくもない
I'm not lonely.
悲しくない 苦しくくない さみしくない
Not sad, not in pain, not lonely.
悲しくない 苦しくない さみしくない
ああ もう うるさいな
Ah, it's so noisy now.
うおーー
Woah—
どこまでも沈む
Sinking forever,
神さまでさえ見つけられないくらい
deep enough that even God can't find me.
深く 深く 沈んでいく
Deeper and deeper I sink,
なまぬるい熱帯夜
through this lukewarm tropical night.
乾いた体温に響くレクイエム
A requiem echoing in dry body temperature.
世界が私だけを置いていく
The world is leaving me behind.
泡になってなくなるなんて 美しい終わりはきっとこない
A beautiful end like turning into foam won't ever come.
魂一つままならないし 世界は不完全で果てがないもの
Even a single soul is unmanageable; the world is imperfect and endless.
濡れて張り付いた孤独が冷え切って
The wet, clinging loneliness has frozen over,
いつまでも私を雁字搦めにしている
keeping me bound forever.
この薄暗い胎に佇んだ
Standing in this dim womb,
永遠の終わらせ方を知らないまま
still not knowing how to end eternity.
揺らいでは夜中 水面解く静寂と証を
Swaying in the middle of the night, the silence and evidence unraveling on the water's surface.
吐いて消そうとしてる 帰れないどこも私が狂っている
Trying to exhale and erase it; I can't go back anywhere, I'm going crazy.
かじかんだ身体が離れていく
My numbed body is drifting away.
何も感じたくない もう
I don't want to feel anything anymore.
どこまでも落ちる
Falling forever,
朝焼けでさえ照らしきれないように
so that even the sunrise can't illuminate me.
暗く 暗く 溺れていく
Drowning in the darkness,
なまぬるい熱帯夜
this lukewarm tropical night.
一ドル銀貨の月さえ見放す
Even the moon, like a silver dollar coin, abandons me.
エヴァーブルー 染まっては続く夢なら
Ever blue; if this dream continues as I'm stained by it,
乾いた夜風に燃えるレクイエム
a requiem burning in the dry night breeze.
世界が私だけを置いていく
The world is leaving me behind.
NEXT GUEST
HOLOLIVE GAMERS
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
2 MIX
Lazyroop
はあ 日曜日の朝 気分は少しブルー
Sigh, Sunday morning, feeling a bit blue.
今週も終わっちゃうな いや困っちゃうな
This week is ending too; oh, what a bother.
やりたいこと山積みだ
I've got a mountain of things I want to do.
そうどうやったって来る月曜日
Yeah, no matter what I do, Monday comes.
きっと囲まれてんだ鉄格子
I'm surely surrounded by iron bars.
いつか解き放たれたい 「でも一人じゃ笑えない」
I want to be set free someday— "But I can't smile alone."
吹き抜ける風と踊った
I danced with the wind blowing through.
あぁ 沈む夕日にだって
Ah, even in the setting sun,
あぁ 昇る朝日だって
ah, even in the rising sun,
あぁ 雨に打たれたって
ah, even if I'm caught in the rain,
そばにいられたら
as long as I can be by your side.
ループループする毎日が 彩りに溢れてくよ
These looping days are overflowing with color.
きっと さんざめく花火のそばに 香る夢のように
Surely, like a fragrant dream beside the noisy fireworks.
こんな ループループする毎日が かけがえない宝石のように
If these looping days feel like irreplaceable jewels,
大切に思えるのなら
if I can hold them dear,
週末の夜も愛しいね
then even the weekend nights are lovely.
喜怒哀楽　感情の裏の裏に
Joy, anger, pathos, and humor... Deep behind my emotions,
見え隠れしてた私の合図
my signals were appearing and disappearing.
君に届いているのかな
I wonder if they're reaching you.
ああ　春の木陰だって
Ah, even in the shade of spring trees,
ああ　夏の日差しだって
ah, even in the summer sunlight,
ああ　冬の刹那だって
ah, even in the winter's fleeting moments...
秋が来なければ
If autumn doesn't come...
ループループする毎日が　彩りに溢れてくよ
The loop-looping days are overflowing with color.
きっと　さんざめく花火の側に　香る夢のように
Surely, like a dream scented by the bustling fireworks.
こんなループループする毎日が
These loop-looping days...
かけがえない宝石のように
...like irreplaceable jewels.
いつか大切に思えるのなら
If I can think of them as precious someday,
週末の夜も　きらめいて
even the weekend nights will sparkle.
憂鬱な夜も　愛しいね
Even the melancholy nights are lovely.
NEXT GUEST
HOLOLIVE 2ND GENERATION
NAKIRI AYAME
いよーっ　ぽぽぽぽぽ
Yo! Popopopopo!
宵の余、良い！
The night's remainder is good!
百鬼夜行　あんたわちゃちゃ
Hyakkiyagou (Night Parade)... You're all bustling about.
今夜は眠れない
I can't sleep tonight.
連日連夜　遊びつくさん
Day and night, let's play to our hearts' content.
漫才　一打　打　打　打　打
Comedy performance, one hit, hit, hit, hit, hit.
支離滅裂　溢れてくる
Incoherent thoughts come overflowing.
くすぐる好奇心
Tickling my curiosity.
優柔不断　これで決めよう
Indecisive? Let's decide with this.
じゃんけんぽん　あいこでしょ
Rock-paper-scissors! It's a tie!
パッとパッと開いた
Pop, pop, it opened up!
良い？　良い？　良い？
Good? Good? Good?
アッとおっと匂わせる
Surprising and hinting at something,
花火を打ち上げよう
let's set off some fireworks!
歌え　それ見よ　舞え　いけよ
Sing! Look at that! Dance! Go for it!
宵宵怪奇の宴
A night of strange and wondrous banquets.
騒げ　よろず集え　嘉例な鬼は外
Make some noise! Gather round! Good demons, stay out!
歌え　それ舞え　ならえばおんぼろ
Sing! Dance! If we line up, we're all worn out,
それすら愛嬌
but even that is charming.
騒げ　暁まで　嘉例な鬼は外
Make some noise until dawn! Good demons, stay out!
阿　是非も無いことだ
Ah, it's inevitable.
喝采を背な　踊り流せ
With cheers at our backs, let's dance them away.
吽　ずっと不世出　派手に舞って
Un, always unparalleled, dancing flashily.
天真爛漫　宵の余、良い！
Naively innocent, the night's remainder is good!
明鏡止水　目を瞑って
Clear and serene, close your eyes.
ひと息入れちゃって
Take a little breath.
美味味　味わったら
Once you've tasted the deliciousness,
感無量　打　打　打　打　打
deeply moved, hit, hit, hit, hit, hit.
永劫回帰　終わりたくない
Eternal recurrence, I don't want it to end.
何して遊ぼうか
What shall we play?
暗中模索　これで決めよう
Groping in the dark? Let's decide with this.
じゃんけんぽん　あいこでしょ
Rock-paper-scissors! It's a tie!
グッとグッと堪えて
Firmly, firmly hold it in.
良い？　良い？　良い？
Good? Good? Good?
ワクとワクを綻ばせ
Let the excitement burst forth,
最高を打ち鳴らそう
let's ring out the best times!
泣いて　笑え　読み続け
Cry, laugh, and keep on reading...
きらきらびびか輝け
...and shine brilliantly!
おいで　鼓舞をせぬ　嘉例な鬼は外
Come on over! Don't be discouraged! Good demons, stay out!
泣いて　笑え　舞い進め
Cry, laugh, and dance forward!
東奔西走　何でも良いぞ
Running all over the place, anything goes!
おいで　遠慮も無用　嘉例な鬼は外
Come on over! No need for restraint! Good demons, stay out!
阿　惚けちゃいそうな夜を飾る
Ah, decorating the night that makes me space out.
眩しい声に　連れられて
Led by the dazzling voices,
阿　端から端まで最高派手に舞って
Ah, from end to end, dancing most flashily.
天真爛漫　宵の余、良い！
Naively innocent, the night's remainder is good!
トワ様3周年おめでとー！
Towa-sama, happy 3rd anniversary!
お嬢ありがとう！
Ojou, thank you!
よいしょー！
Yoisho-!
一緒にアイドルしちゃおうと思うよ！
I'm thinking we should be idols together!
オッケー、次いっくよ！
Okay, let's go for the next one!
いくよ！
Here we go!
せーの！
One, two!
ヨッヨッ ヨヨイのヨイのヨヨイ
Yo-yo-yo-yoi no yoi no yo-yoi
しゃしゃしゃのヨイヨイ 浮世満たす
Sha-sha-sha no yoi yoi, filling the floating world
しゃしゃしゃのヨイヨイ 幻世を埋め尽くせ
Sha-sha-sha no yoi yoi, fill up the transient world
歌え 踊れ 右に回れ
Sing, dance, turn to the right
いよっ ぴかいちの 歌者
Yo-ho! The number one singer
さあさ 騒げ 夜に集え
Come on, make some noise, gather in the night
可憐な鬼はうち
Lovely demons are inside
歌え 踊れ 前習え
Sing, dance, follow the lead
えいっ 骨の髄まで 哀嬌
Hup! Charming to the marrow of the bone
さあさ 騒げ 暁まで
Come on, make some noise, until dawn
可憐な鬼はうち
Lovely demons are inside
ああ 敷居踏まない コンカイカッサイ
Ah, don't step on the threshold, this time applause
騒ぐ 音に乗せられて
Carried away by the noisy sound
なんだかんだ せないあてに舞って
One way or another, dancing for no reason
天真爛漫 ヨイのヨヨイ！
Naivety and innocence, yoi no yoyoi!
NEXT GUEST
大空スバル Oozora Subaru
Oozora Subaru
ギラギラの太陽が
The glittering sun
ワクワクが待ちきれない
Can't wait for the excitement
あれもしたい これもしたい
I want to do this and that
Endless Summer Time
太陽少女 作詞: Mitsu(TRYTONELABO) 作曲・編曲: TAKT(TRYTONELABO)
Taiyou Shoujo Lyrics: Mitsu(TRYTONELABO) Composition/Arrangement: TAKT(TRYTONELABO)
青い空と
The blue sky and
白い雲が
The white clouds
心のボルテージ上げてゆく
Raising my heart's voltage
ラムネ色の
Ramune-colored
Tシャツはね
T-shirt, you know
今年一番のオススメ
Is my top recommendation this year
走り出した 海岸線
Starting to run along the coastline
どこまでだって行けそうだね
Feels like we can go anywhere
数えきれない 冒険チャレンジ
Countless adventure challenges
君も一緒に行こう
You come with us too
あっという間に進んでく時計
The clock is moving so fast
短すぎちゃいない？ Summer Time
Isn't it too short? Summer Time
全部最高のメモリアルにして
Making everything the best memorial
追い風
Tailwind
みんな連れてけ
Take everyone along
素晴らしい太陽がさぁさぁ
The wonderful sun is, come on
せーのでジャンプ 弾ける汗
Jump on 'one-two', splashing sweat
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels
眩しく輝け
Shine brightly
ギラギラの太陽が
The glittering sun
ドキドキがいっぱいで
Full of heart-throbbing
あれもしよう これもやろう
Let's do this and that
Endless Summer Time
涼しい風
A cool breeze
寝転がって
Lying down
のびのびとお昼寝本当
Taking a nap freely, truly
夢の中は
Inside the dream
なんだってできちゃう
I can do anything
キラキラ光るよ スーパースター
Shining brightly, a superstar
流れ星を
A shooting star
見つけに行こう
Let's go find it
夜更かししたってへっちゃらだよ
Staying up late is no problem at all
願い事が
When wishes
溢れそうな時は
Are about to overflow
ミルキーウェイにダイブ
Dive into the Milky Way
ちょっとくらい下手だって平気
It's okay to be a little bit bad
みんながくれるファイトがある
I have the fight that everyone gives me
どこまでだって駆け抜けてゆけるから
Because I can keep running through anywhere
行くよね
We're going, right?
準備 OK？
Ready OK?
ひとつひとつが
Each and every one
全部全部が
All of them
届いてるから 上を向いて
Have reached me, so look up
体中に
All over the body
息を吸い込んだなら
If you take a deep breath
叫ぶよ
I'll shout it out
みんな大好き
I love you all
毎日が記念日になれ
Let every day be an anniversary
君の心 照らし灯そう
I'll light up and illuminate your heart
新しげな勇気を丸ごと
Giving you all of my fresh courage
お届けしちゃうよ
I'll deliver it to you
空の彼方まで飛んでいこう
Let's fly to the other side of the sky
せーのでジャンプ 弾ける汗
Jump on 'one-two', splashing sweat
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels
眩しく輝け
Shine brightly
ギラギラの太陽さ！
I'm a dazzling sun!
欲張っていっちゃいます！
I'm going to be greedy!
あれもしたい！ これもしたい！
I want to do that! I want to do this!
レッツ サマータイム！
Let's summer time!
NEXT GUEST
HOLOLIVE GAMERS
大神ミオ / OOKAMI MIO
Ookami Mio
静寂に響いてよ My howling
Let it echo in the silence, my howling
Howling
作詞・作曲：ZAQ / 編曲：KanadeYUK
Lyrics & Composition: ZAQ / Arrangement: KanadeYUK
滔々と流れていく風景
The scenery that flows on and on
刹那的な日々の中で
In these ephemeral days
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand reached out was gentle
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
A premonition of a slight fever dripping into my heartbeat
風に逆らう
Against the wind
そう生きてきたから
That's how I've lived
君に会って気付く
Meeting you made me realize
「もう独りじゃない」
“I'm not alone anymore”
灼光 瞬きを越え 描き 月へ響く
Burning light, crossing over the blinking, drawing and echoing to the moon
爪弾く道 金瞳の群れ 共に嘆く夜
A strumming path, a pack of golden eyes, a night where we mourn together
慟哭 伝播する想いは心強くする
Wailing, the spreading feelings make us stronger
ついておいでよ
Come with me
後ろに君がいるから 私は迷わない
Because you are behind me, I won't hesitate
光射す道へ
To the path where the light shines
無力だだから 仲間を求め
Because I'm powerless, I seek companions
凍えるから 火を灯して
Because I'm freezing, light a fire
変化とともに 進化していく
Evolving along with the changes
この結末は だれも知らない
This ending, no one knows
君を信じる そう決めているから
I believe in you, because I've decided so
どんな異常・非日常も
No matter how strange or unusual
乗り越えられるよ
We can overcome it
月光 この闇に唯一 凛と咲く華
Moonlight, the only flower blooming with dignity in this darkness
恐れなのか 憧れなのか 向かい合う夜空
Is it fear or longing? The night sky we face
大地を駆け抜ける私と君が創り出す
You and I, running through the earth, will create
この物語 単純未来じゃない 湧き立つ情熱
This story, not a simple future, but a surging passion
この声に乗せよう
Let's put it in this voice
空飛ぶ羽根なくても 手は繋げられたから
Even without wings to fly, we were able to hold hands
この運命を選んだ
So I chose this destiny
鼓動する遠吠えは 静寂に響いて
The pulsating howl echoes in the silence
何度も何度も その絆を確かめあった
Over and over again, we confirmed that bond
瞬きを越え 描き 月へ響く
Crossing over the blinking, drawing and echoing to the moon
爪弾く道 金瞳の群れ 共に嘆く夜
A strumming path, a pack of golden eyes, a night where we mourn together
慟哭 伝播する想いは心強くする
Wailing, the spreading feelings make us stronger
共にいこうよ
Let's go together
隣に君がいるから 私は迷わない
Because you are beside me, I won't hesitate
光射す道へ
To the path where the light shines
Listen to my howling...
鼓動が止まることはない
The heartbeat will never stop
大切フォトグラフ
作詞：篠崎あやと / 作曲・編曲：本多友紀 (Arte Refact)
Taisetsu Photograph
Lyrics: Ayato Shinozaki / Composition & Arrangement: Yuki Honda (Arte Refact)
見慣れきったドアの先に
Beyond the familiar door
変わらない微笑み
An unchanging smile
ふいにギュッと抱きしめたら
If I suddenly hug you tight
ほら また笑顔が咲いたよ
Look, a smile has bloomed again
撮り貯めた日常を
The daily life I've captured and saved
寄せ書きみたいに集めてさ
Collected like a collection of messages
さよならは胸にしまって
Keeping goodbyes in my heart
肩を寄せて 飽きるくらい話そう
Leaning shoulder to shoulder, let's talk until we're tired of it
限りない想い出
Boundless memories
ポケットに詰め込んで
Packed into my pocket
挫けそうな時も 共に支え合える
Even when we're about to give up, we can support each other
大切フォトグラフ
Precious photograph
遥か未来の先へ
To the far future ahead
これからも一緒だよ
We'll be together from now on, too
思いっきり笑おう 手を繋ぎ歌おう
Let's laugh with all our might, hold hands and sing
この一瞬が いつまでも大好き
I'll love this moment forever
立ち止まって 落ち込む日も
On days I stop and feel down
たまにはいいよね
That's okay once in a while, isn't it?
わかちあって 寄り添えたら
If we can share and stay close
涙も想い出に変わる
Even tears will turn into memories
ささやかな幸せは
Small happinesses are
飾らない毎日の中にあって
In the midst of unadorned daily life
ふとした会話や
Casual conversations and
隣歩く日々が 宝物なんだ
the days we walk side by side are treasures
想い出は溢れて
Memories are overflowing
両手じゃ足りないよ
Both hands aren't enough
嬉しさも辛さも 共に笑い合える
Sharing both joy and pain, we can laugh together
大切フォトグラフ
Precious photograph
最高の笑顔と
With the best smiles and
とびっきり幸せを
extraordinary happiness
大好きなみんなへ 少し擽ったいけど
To everyone I love, though it's a bit ticklish
いつもありがとね
Thanks for everything, as always
遥か未来の先へ
To the far future ahead
これからも一緒だよ
We'll be together from now on, too
思いっきり笑おう 手を繋ぎ歌おう
Let's laugh with all our might, hold hands and sing
この一瞬が いつまでも大好き
I'll love this moment forever
はーい、みんな！どうだったかなー？
Hi, everyone! How was it?
ドキドキしたー！
My heart was pounding!
いつもありがとね、みんなありがとう！
Thanks for everything, thank you everyone!
ということで！常闇トワ3周年記念ライブ！
And so! Tokoyami Towa's 3rd Anniversary Live!
最高でしたねー！
It was the best, wasn't it!
語彙力どこ行った？
Where did my vocabulary go?
はい。もうね、見てください！さっき踊りましたこのステージ！
Yes. Look! This stage where I just danced!
このステージもね、あのー、作ってもらいました！
This stage too, was made for me!
トワのいっぱいわがままを聞いて、素敵なステージにしてくれました！
They listened to Towa's requests and made it a wonderful stage!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あのね、最後までね、今日はね、見てほしいんです！
You see, I want you to watch until the very end today!
なんと素晴らしいことが、3つ、4つ？3つ、4つあります！
There are wonderful things, three, four? Three or four of them!
では！告知させていただきたいと思います！
So! I'd like to make some announcements!
まず一つ目！こちら、ボーン！
First one! This, boom!
常闇トワ3周年記念グッズセットが発売しまーす！
Towa's 3rd Anniversary Goods set will be on sale!
はい！最高だー、ありがとう、最高！
Yes! It's the best, thank you, the best!
常闇トワ 活動3周年記念
Tokoyami Towa 3rd Anniversary
...あとグッズの内容はこちらポン！
...and here's the details on the merch! Bam!
はい、この4点になっておりまして、
1つは特典になるんですけど、
Yes, there are these four items.
One of them is a bonus...
3点と特典になっております。
じゃあ細かい内容見ていきましょう、まず1つ目はこちら！
...so it's 3 items plus a bonus.
Let's look at the details. First is this!
キャンバスボードになっております！
The Canvas Board!
イラストはメロ先生に描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Mero-sensei!
映画の一部みたいじゃない？これ、すごくない？
Doesn't it look like a scene from a movie?
Isn't this amazing?
ポニテ可愛いでしょ！
The ponytail is cute, right?
可愛いでしょこれ、キャンバスボード可愛い。
It's cute, isn't it? The canvas board is cute.
はい、コメント盛り上がり、ホイ！ハハッ！
Okay, get hyped in the comments! Whoo! Haha!
はい、ということで2個目はこちら。
Alright, moving on to the second item.
常闇トワモチーフタオル！
The Tokoyami Towa Motif Towel!
ということで、もうくそエモエモエモエモなデザインを...
This design is just... super, super emotional...
デザインです。
...it's the design.
今日のね、日付も入っておりますので、
ぜひぜひチェックしてください。
It even has today's date on it,
so please check it out.
ということでラスト一個はこちら、パーン！
And the final item is this! Bam!
ビビスマホリングとなっております！
The Bibi Smartphone Ring!
これ超可愛くない？
Isn't this super cute?
良いでしょう！
Nice, right?
これね、スマートフォンにつけてずっと一緒だよ。
You can attach it to your phone and be together forever.
ずっと一緒だよ、っていうことでよろしくね！
Together forever! Hope you like it!
はい、ではこの3つフルセットを買っていただきますと、バーン！
Now, if you buy the full set of these three items... Bam!
はい、ボーン！タイミングは神すぎる。
Yes! Boom! The timing was perfect.
えっと、直筆...あ、違います。
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます！
Um, a handwr— wait, no.
It comes with a foil-stamped replica message postcard!
数量限定にはなるんですけど、サイン、直筆サインもありますので、
ぜひぜひゲットしてね！
They are limited in quantity, but some have handwritten signatures,
so get yours!
はい、ということで一つ目の告知はこちら、グッズになりました。
So, the first announcement was the merchandise.
概要欄に貼っているので、10時ぐらいになったら
パッカリーするんじゃないでしょうか、皆さんよろしくね。
The link is in the description. Sales should start
around 10:00, I think. Check it out!
はい、ということで何とまだあるんです。二つ目はこちら！バーン！
But wait, there's more! The second one is this! Bam!
常闇トワ、LINEスタンプができました！
Tokoyami Towa LINE stickers are now available!
こんやぴとか、言葉は刃とか、メンタルメンタルとか...
'Kon-Yapi', 'Words are blades', 'Mental, mental'...
小太郎とビビとほっぺスリスリみたいな、
可愛いスタンプをのいみね先生が描いてくれました。
Noimine-sensei drew these cute stickers,
like Kotaro and Bibi rubbing cheeks.
これもね、10時頃には販売されてるんじゃないのでしょうか、ボボーン！
These should also be on sale around 10:00! Bo-boom!
ぜひこの配信が終わったらチェックしてみてくださいね。
Please check them out after this stream ends.
あー、で唾を飲み込んどいて...
Ah, let me take a sip...
はい、ということで何と告知まだあります！三つ目、何とデカいです！
Okay, there's still another announcement! The third one is huge!
三つ目はこちら、バーン！
The third one is this! Bam!
日清焼そばU.F.O.と常闇トワのコラボが決定！！
A collaboration between Nissin Yakisoba U.F.O.
and Tokoyami Towa is confirmed!!
うおー！ドンドンパフパフ！コメントも大盛り上がり！
Whoo! *Celebration noises*! The comments are going wild!
詳しくはね、1月13日金曜日の11時、
日清焼そばU.F.O.公式Twitterをチェックしてください！
For more details, check the Nissin Yakisoba U.F.O.
official Twitter on Jan 13th (Fri) at 11:00 AM!
うおー！大盛り上がりです！
Whoo! Major hype!
テーマは「アクマ的旨さ、感じてみろや」となっておりまして...
The theme is "Taste the devilish deliciousness"...
内容盛りだくさんの企画なのでお楽しみに！
It's a project packed with content, so please look forward to it!
今ね、トワはね、もう準備を準備をしてますので、
楽しみにしてて下さいな！
Towa is currently getting things ready, so stay tuned!
はい、ということで三つ告知をしましたが、
何とサプライズで後もう一つありまして...
Alright, that's three announcements...
but there's a surprise fourth one!
何と新曲があります！
There's a new song!
新曲なんですけど、作詞・作曲・編曲はキノさんに作っていただきまして...
The new song was written, composed, and arranged by quino!
まあ、「石の上にも三年」ですか、三年経つことは本当にすごいことだということで、
トワも今日で三年経ちました。
Well, "three years on a stone," they say. Three years is a long time.
Today marks my 3rd anniversary.
本当にね、やっぱりトワ声とか性格もそうなんだけど
ちょっと自分に自信がないとこがあったんだけど...
Actually, regarding my voice and personality...
I used to lack confidence in myself.
その中でもね、みんなに見つけてもらえて、本当に嬉しかったし、
感謝の気持ちがずっとあります。
But even so, you all found me.
I'm so happy and forever grateful.
でその感謝の気持ち、「見つけてくれてありがとう」とか、
その感謝の気持ちを歌詞に乗せてほしいですとご依頼しまして...
I asked for those feelings of gratitude, like "Thank you for finding me,"
to be in the lyrics...
素敵な、ちょっと恋愛っぽいソングになっております。
...and it's become a lovely, somewhat romantic song.
なのでね、エモい雰囲気で聴いていただければと思います。
So, please listen to it in an emotional mood.
はい、ではここまで聞いていただき見ていただきありがとうございました。
Thank you all for listening and watching until now.
最後一曲、心を込めて歌うので聴いてください。サンピタリア。
I'll sing this last song with all my heart. Please listen. "Sanpitaria".
黙って俯いて
Keeping quiet, looking down,
空の色さえ知らない私の声で君が笑った
You laughed at my voice, though I didn't even know the color of the sky.
あの日から世界は眩しくて
Since that day, the world has been so bright,
私は私を好きになって
And I've come to love myself.
晴れて
...and clear,
なくさないように 息をする
I take a breath so I won't lose it.
サンピタリア
作詞・作曲・編曲：keeno
Sunpitallia
Lyrics, Composition & Arrangement: keeno
眩むような青空の真ん中で今も泣いているのは
In the middle of a blinding blue sky, the one who is still crying...
君が映る世界が 悲しくなるほど優しいから
...is because the world reflecting you is so painfully kind.
苦しくなるほど遠いから
Because it's so painfully far away.
じくじくと疼く甘い熱は 閉じ込めていたのに
I'd locked away this sweet, throbbing fever,
痛くて零れた
but the pain made it spill out.
君と私の体と体の間にある
Between your body and mine,
酷く薄い皮膚さえ もう邪魔になるくらい
even this terribly thin skin feels like an obstacle.
その鼓膜 その心臓 ずっと奥にさわられたら
If you touch my eardrums, my heart, deep inside...
君はまた笑うのかな
I wonder if you'll smile again.
ねえどうか君まで届け
Hey, please, let it reach you.
強がって笑った
I put on a tough face and laughed,
息を呑むような橙の中で
within this breathtaking orange glow.
君が見てる世界の隅っこでいいからいさせて
In a corner of the world you see, just let me be there.
どこでもいいから私を見て
Anywhere is fine, just look at me.
ねえ 明日は晴れかな雨かななんて
Hey, wondering if tomorrow will be sunny or rainy...
そんなこと当たり前に思えるのは
the reason I can think of such things as natural...
君がいたから
is because you were here.
でもね今もこの胸を締め付ける空の色に
But you know, even now, the color of the sky tightens my chest.
立ち尽くしたまま動けないのは
The reason I stand frozen and unable to move...
頬が濡れていくのは君のせいだ
and my cheeks getting wet, it's all your fault.
そんなこと思ってしまったの
I ended up thinking that...
思ってしまったんだ
I ended up thinking that.
私ひとつ分の涙じゃ 全然足りないくらいに
With just my own tears, it's not nearly enough;
涸れそうでひび割れて 心が止まりそうなの
parched and cracked, my heart feels like it'll stop.
言葉にしようとすればするほど
The more I try to put it into words,
嗚咽になって溶け出して しまうから
the more it turns into sobs and melts away.
君と私の体と体の間にある
Between your body and mine,
呼吸も温度も もう邪魔になるくらい
even our breath and warmth feel like obstacles.
その鼓膜 その心臓
Those eardrums, that heart,
ずっと奥にさわるから
because I'll touch you deep inside.
私を見付けてよ
Find me.
壊れても叫ぶから
Even if I break, I'll keep shouting.
ねえどうか君まで届け
Hey, please, let it reach you.
3年間ありがとう！
Thank you for the past three years!
これからも、4年目もよろしくね！みんな大好きだよ！
Please keep supporting me in the 4th year! I love you all!
解！
Solve!
脱！
Escape!
脱獄を叶えようぜ
Let's make our prison break happen
ずっと伝えたかった！でも一人じゃない！
I've always wanted to tell you! But I'm not alone!
いつか届きたかった！でも一人じゃない！
I wanted to reach it someday! But I'm not alone!
瞳は孤高に
With eyes of solitude
瞬く
Twinkling
道
Path
3周年の3年間、トワをそばで応援し続けてくれた子悪魔のみんな！
To all the Kenzoku who have supported Towa for these 3 years!
そして3年間、常闇トワを応援してくれたみんな、本当にありがとう！
And to everyone who supported Tokoyami Towa for 3 years, thank you!
正直、周りに流され、自分を失いかけたこともあったけれど、
To be honest, there were times I almost lost myself,
みんながいてくれたおかげで、今の自分が一番好き。
but thanks to you all, I like who I am now the most.
これからも、よりトワらしく常闇トワを更新していけたら幸せだと思います。
I'll be happy if I can keep growing as Tokoyami Towa in my own way.
みんなともっと、マイペースに歩んでいけたら、周りの景色ももっときれいにみえそう。
If I can walk at my own pace with you, the view will look even better.
そんなときもトワの背中を押してくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be glad if you could keep pushing me forward at those times too.
これからも『今の自分がいちばん好き』って言えるように
So that I can continue to say 'I like myself right now the most',
自分を、自分の曲を、大切にしていきたいと思います。
I want to cherish myself and my music.
みんなも自分を大切にしてね！これからもよろしくね！
Please take care of yourselves too! I'm counting on you!
最後に、開催されたLIVE最高に楽しかった！！大好きだよ トワ 2024.1.3
Finally, the LIVE was so much fun!! I love you all. - Towa 2024.1.3